All right. Hello. Welcome everyone. This
is Active Inferrance stream number 16.1.
It's December 2nd, 2025.
I'm going to start the stream with a
GitHub push. Everything is on the GitHub
repo docology template.
We will reload that.
And we're live. Looking forward to your
comments and any ideas or questions in
the chat. Here is where we are going
today. We are going to a test-driven
development configurable end to end test
suite operation
data analysis and visualization
validation steps and PDF rendering
including with citations and clickable
links and equations formatted as a
scientific PDF
as well as a variety of other fun
formats
including HTML ML files that can be
opened for the web and slides
or conversion to slides.
That's the PDF rendering functionality.
There is a LLM review output section
that um
provides review and improvements and
suggestions for the manuscript in
English. there's a translation
uh output using LLM locally to
translate.
Then there are
literature database search
and through APIs and PDF download and
local LLM summarization which we're
going to use. So without getting too far
ahead of oursel, let's go to the agenda.
Okay, the title of the stream is
actionable templated driven research,
which is going to get at the core of
what this template repo is, operational
meta-accientific arts and crafts, which
I guess is like the genre. The stream is
live on YouTube on the active inference
institute channel. This will be a live
stream interactive walkth through and we
can also do some improvements and some
uh other random stuff. See where it
goes. Greetings up cycle. Good to see
you. Tools. I'm using a Mac computer.
Cursor 2.146
with mostly the auto and the OP recently
released available at a discount opus
4.5
and locally
O Lama will be using Llama 3 and Quen
type models.
Okay, here in this
we can
look at this on GitHub.
There's a few big themes that are going
to come up and I'm sure many more. This
is just a first step. There's going to
be a big focus on end toend
configurability
and ease of reproducibility.
There's going to be the usage of a lot
of thin orchestrators in articulated
reference which means that the modular
flexible methods are underlying in a
kind of single composable toolkit
uh set of affordances and orchestration
happens separated from those tools which
gives good ability to express different
workflows and swap out different tool
implementations.
There's going to be a two layer model to
this repo overall, which I might as well
describe here.
The project folder is a self-contained
and is intended to be at the project
level, like the specific research paper
that's going to get generated. And this
is going to be a testdriven
package alongside a manuscript expressed
in these modular markdown files which
are undergoing this internal coherence
test suite which could be zero tests or
you could use it extensively
with the SRC code orchestrated through
tests [snorts] and scripts
which in the context of a certain
formatting for the manuscripts.
in markdown.
Now pop out of the project
is going to be utilized by the template
repo using the infrastructure modules
and the scripts in the infrastructure
and ultimately this top level run.sh at
the top level which is going to pop up
this main menu where we can run the
tests, we could render the manuscript,
we could run the scientific review.
We'll just start that one up now.
So here we already uh in this
I have these tabs here is one process
going with the local LOM summarizing
papers that were downloaded from a
literature search.
Um we'll look at that step. Here is the
output of the translation into Chinese,
Hindi, Russian.
Here's
the manuscript rendering which uh
includes the full test suite test suite
within the project level of the
SRC here with respect to these tests
within the project and then the
infrastructure level tests which are in
the top level test
folder. So double test suite
then running the scientific analysis
which is the SRC orchestration within
the project. So here it's like a
template paper about optimization
methods. Then section by section
going through the manuscript
markdowns
that was the analysis and scientific
figure generation.
Then
there's discovery of manuscript sections
and for each manuscript section they're
generated into the PDF,
the HTML, any other formats.
Then the PDFs are concatenated to make
project combined.
There's validation of the subtypes.
The subtypes are copied from output
within project
which is intended to be a kind of
monopilletic standalone kind of
briefcase and then it gets copied for
convenience to the top level so we can
always have the most recent version of
the top level just as a convenience.
After copying those outputs, there's the
local LLM scientific review.
And then here is the um warm-up
executive summary. And this is is going
to um
that is
here. LLM
output project output LLM combine review
improvement suggestions.
Um
beautiful hallucinations and all.
Uh,
so here is what that looks like when
it's running. This is the
English scientific review
of the
current manuscript.
This one is on the translation step. We
already have them, so I'll just cancel
it. And here's the summarization. So
this is kind of the other branch. So you
can for this repo you can use them
together as I hope we will do so in the
coming minutes.
Um or you could just you could
just use the
um keyword search and PDF download
summarization pipeline
which looks like this. We'll make lit
search
dot slash run
literature search and PDF download 7.
This is going to search archive and
semantic scholar for papers. Download
PDFs, add them to the bib library,
generate AI summary, and you can set how
many parallel workers.
We're going to do um
30 papers per keyword.
Search keywords
epistemic foraging.
Um, resume previous run. No, start a
fresh run.
So, this is going to search archive
for Epistemic Forging.
Um, found 30 results,
58 dduplicated from Semantic Scholar and
Archive.
The um literature output is saved into a
top level folder called literature.
The references.bib
is kind of overleaf latex style
bibliography
and the PDFs are downloaded into PDFs
folder.
Then the summaries are made by the same
name in the summaries folder and we're
going to use that too. Very fun effect I
believe and that's kind of chugging away
here. So especially with a possibly
slightly better naming scheme or
biblioraphic reference system there
could be calculation as I know some
teams at the institute and other teams
have done to make sort of all of archive
scale summarization or work with
embeddings other methods but the overall
spirit here is this sort of visible
craft arts and craft script style that
it it it sits sits in a nice space in in
morphospace for programs.
Um we will use cursor as a pseudo rag to
work with these summaries as context to
write researchbased papers that are
going to transform
the package inside of project and the
manuscript. And then we're going to
bounce this off each other and get
grounded interpretable step by step.
Could be entirely manual or could be
entirely AI orchestrated
with some end toend
literature based
augmented research multi-channel repo
versioning.
So
let's go to some of the more themes.
Uh yeah, two-layer science is the top
level of the repo with the
infrastructure which is kind of like the
oven mitts and then there's project
which is like the dish coming out of the
oven. So the two-layer science is the
meta-cience
tools for operations in the repo of
template and then project could be plain
text markdown for a purely pros
philosophy paper or there could be a
simple coin flip and the insertion of
the outputs of the coin flip or a
visualization based upon data for a
philosophy paper or it could be
extremely technical could modularly
compose all these kinds of reference
across within sections, papers, all
these different kinds of things. By
knowing that we're going to use that
state space or want to have those kinds
of literature expression
in making a
project pipeline that could be more
software with sort of sloughing off
documentation or it could be more manual
pros and I never entered into it.
uh modular minds within and across
nested blankets. What kinds of
compositionality for agent tools? We can
add a MCP or other tool layer. There's
already a CLI.
uh meta-cience, open science,
philosophy, second order science, all
these kinds of questions about tool
building uh eyides wide open as opposed
to the alternative using even cursor
other kilo code other um code augmented
approaches
and just more generally tools to think
with and sense making and personal
collective knowledge management how
that's related to file versioning.
this idea that is big in the DI and meta
science uh spaces with version
controlling and some of the work with
claims graphs and different ways to
parse and connect some of the entity
reference and semantics and different
granularities of analyzing and
integrating research papers. uh pseudo
make me a manuscript
basically role-based access including
total root access to research projects
for end to end configurable
reproducibility including the PDF
rendering exactly a certain way
and blurring the line using formal
ALO reference as well as cursor shared
contextualization
blurring the line with command, code,
knowledge base, all these different
kinds of synthetic intelligence
semantics which is sort of like the
pragmatics and semantics within
the augmented IDE which can run code as
well as use these softer language
affordances.
Um, a lot of ways to use the modularity
of the infrastructure level and the
project level to make packages that are
conceivably simpler as well as possibly
just different or more modular by adding
a module to either the infrastructure
level or within the project level,
which we can do during this stream.
and
exploring I think a very creative
tension with industrialization and
regularization normalization
automation.
There's going to be some areas to to
explore about preparing one's workspace
and operations in the niche and sort of
to carve one spoon with a knife out of
wood. It might be a different startup
time or tool need rather than a wooden
spoon or a metal spoon factory. But
these are all just these different
morphologies, different energy
gradients, information gradients of
production. And so what that looks like
in a sort of cognitive
semantic information, niche
modification,
multi-agentic setting.
the potter's wheel. Censoring projects
before shaping them and making small
changes that radiate out through natural
forces and and these defined flows.
The apprentices advantage learning by
structured doing so supporting a niche
where a sidefolder like journal or uh
field notes. other modular systems can
be brought in and and tested in a
relatively standalone or in a very
deeply integrated way. So with these
kinds of niche artifacts as the trace
but also with their own
activity and informiveness
intraactivity
in cases as with others we encounter in
the niche. So holding up and open that
whole continuum from datalike to active
like that kind of polycomputing
relational feature.
All right, let's go to the agenda and
meanwhile if you're watching live make a
suggestion. I will wait to uh a first
suggestion before including that in the
research paper that we will re search
for and write and update the PDF. Maybe
even go all the way to Zenotto at the
end of the stream with a literature
based. So if somebody has a specific
question or uh
topic to research, write it and I'll
wait at least a few minutes for that.
All right.
The way to run this system is to open a
terminal
in the base layer of the repo.
Dot slashrron.sh.
This is a single entry point.
There's going to be
an exit option and eight different kind
of partially overlapping
functionalities.
There's run the infrastructure tests
which is going to be let's start with
that one in this window.
So this is just making sure that all of
the modular functionality
of the template repo
independent of the project whether it's
a a pros journal poetry book or whether
it's a simulation and data download and
integration
that is the two-layer model.
The infrastructure is like the crust and
the project is like the topping of this
scientific pizza or or uh analogous.
So here it's about to finish.
There are 1654
infrastructure
tests. So a huge number of many very
simple tests and it has about 80%
coverage of the codebase of the
infrastructure modules which are the the
build system
which is the PDF composition and
validation the core methods of logging
and interfacing
documentation
and relationships between document
parts.
the literature search methods
for download the LLM methods which here
are only olama local calls
um possibly a vestigial file here
the publishing methods which can be
greatly extended with nanopubs other
kinds of uh onchain off-chain publishing
rendering some of the manuscript
transformation tools that help go from
the markdown with the defined style
guide into the properly linked reference
and checking for the equations, figures,
sections, citations, etc.
Um, possible scientific developer
functionalities
and validation methods that are called
on by other package.
um every folder where it makes sense.
I try to have a both readme a human
readable specific accounting of a file
function structure etc. as well as an
agents.m MD
which can describe more similar
overlapping more technical
sometimes sometimes prioritized
information for augmented coding whether
using kind of like a codeex cloud code
factory AI terminal coding assistant or
headless version or using
uh cursor like which is doing something
similar um under the hood. So that's the
infrastructure test function.
That was option one. Option two is run
project tests.
So here these are within project. This
is 320 tests but which is still a a a
vast relative number
but just as a starting point for
modifying the project package. So this
is using these src functions. no modules
uh as not to overly bias what the format
of the SRC is. Just kind of a flat list
of functionalities
that these tests within the project
again flat covering those file names
test
and then that is the functions that are
going to be used within the package. for
example to generate simulation plots.
So to simulate visualize check data in
general and that's what we're going to
modify based upon
semantics of literature grounded
research summaries.
So was option two does this kind of um
hey that's just how we've always done it
with the high test coverage within the
package and at the infrastructure
uh level.
Okay.
Uh also at the top level of the repo is
docs which is documentation about the
repo and the two layer system and just a
bunch of modular footholds searchable
indexable
useful epistemic signposting information
lot of modularity way ways to improve
that.
Um so that is the uh that was the second
option from run.sh SH which was running
the test suite for the
project
three is the uh rendering of the whole
PDF manuscript. Let's just do that one.
So
it um discovers the project
runs the generation of the simulation
and the visualization
by running an orchestrated order of
scripts within the project folder. So
that the project folder again is kind of
like this complete briefcase unfoldable
source code orchestraable DNA.
Then each of these sections in the
project manuscripts folder
are going to get generated slides.
I will open up a
I'm going to open up a window and just
so we can look at the
um
dashboard. One second.
Okay,
here's the
um rendering of the manuscript finished.
So, it renders into output and then it
gets copied into the top level output
folder.
Here's the raw data
from the simulation.
Here are just the figures
from the analysis
generated by the scripts.
Here are the LLM local LLM based.
Um that's looking now at option five,
the LLM scientific review. in this case
in English
um combined review. Let's look at these
on
GitHub.
So project output ll project
output
here's combined review.
So for context, the paper that we
are
reviewing
is a sort of appropriately
referential example default project
title subtitle example by project author
on today's date. And it is a red letter
absolutely black, white, and red all
over document that's composed
to
a cited
linked
interactive format, but also these other
formats for web.
So let's see if this will open and
brave.
HTML
for website use.
The slides
are saved. So probably some uh
manuscript formatting is going to look
uh
look well structured or not in
uh if you write short paragraphs or long
paragraphs.
Uh it might look good in the slides but
not in the HTML. Maybe some of the
formatting is a little off.
Something like that.
Webs, slides, simulation data,
the
um validated
config, parametered reporting,
plain text, composable reports,
the PDF, [snorts]
latte basis,
bibliography file, and final
linked PDF.
So that's and then the
translation
maybe only goes to top level.
Not sure where those went but there
we'll we'll we'll run the translation.
We'll do so step six.
Okay. So now in this
rename that terminal to translation
here we have summarization happening. So
with this step
okay kill that one.
Right. So that's some of the um
Hello Gabriel export.
That's some of the
manuscript rendering project running
project level deliverables within the
context of you could just be doing that
with all manual writing. Doesn't need
any kind of literature. You could just
delete the bibliography or have a null
bibliography.
So now um
let's look at the step seven and not
eight
or literature search PDF download. So
here
uh I'll see a few more minutes if anyone
has a specific topic that they want to
suggest for which topic to research
uh especially if there's archive papers
on it.
And then we will make a branch of the
template repo
and go end to end on making that well
formatted PDF with literature grounding.
But here's the literature search PDF
download component. We'll just do 10
papers per keyword
expected free energy
interosception
electromagnetic.
We don't want to resume the existing
run.
just picked a few
keywords
could be improvements to the
um API call literature database
methods. So just 10 results from
archive.
I don't think I entered any email or API
for semantic scholar. So hence probably
why the rate limit is getting hit there.
So it's going to search these three
keywords
separately
and maybe just doing archive for certain
topics would be would be a little
faster. Let's keep watching.
Um
some there's several there's about 600
PDFs that I've already downloaded
that are in git ignore as a folder so
they don't go to the
uh GitHub
and then if the PDF of that exact
compos name author year word
if if it's not found it tries to
download
For some of the papers, the current
download methods work, but not for all.
So,
uh,
but for for many, let's see, 14 were
already downloaded for those topics. 20
were newly downloaded, six failed.
So after
um downloading
the terms,
it tries to process those
uh PDFs. So let's look at K 2023. So
this is probably something from the in
uh epistemic foraging
or something. We'll see. So okay
top infrastructure level literature PDF
KO U
W 2023 information seeking
okay
so this is by voter cow
of institute discord fame information
seeking polomial narc
model predictive control through
expected free energy minimization.
So this is a archive paper from
about two years ago
that right now with the llama 3 gradient
language model via o lama is getting
summarized.
So that's going to go into we'll pin
this one
that is going to output in the coming
seconds to minutes
a summarization in the summaries with
the same
with the same file name. So, let's just
look at the PDF, see what it's about,
see what the uh
what the what what what the list brought
in. We'll just read the abstract for
epistemic value.
We propose an adaptive model predictive
controller that balances driving the
system to a goal state and seeking
system observations that are informative
with respect to the parameters of a
nonlinear auto reggressive exogenous
model. The controller's objective
function is derived from an expected
free energy functional and contains
information theoretic terms expressing
uncertainty over model parameters and
output predictions.
Experiments illustrate how parameter
uncertainty affects the control
objective and evaluate the proposed
controller for the pendulum swing up
task. And that's getting summarized
here. Greetings paradoxical AP.
So this uh
here's the translation
outputs [snorts]
that is in template project output lm
translation.
Maybe not.
Okay. Say love you.
Okay. So now here
456word summary of this cow paper was
written that's going to be in literature
summaries
how 2023 that was previously not there.
So this is just using the O Lama
local LLM to summarize the
uh paper that we just read. Okay.
So those are the two branches of
functionality
that are at the infrastructure level
that enable different kinds of project
level work.
So let's kill the processes
and then take the project in a specific
applied direction.
So
check in here. I'm going to make a new
uh branch that's going to use the tools
in their functioning state for main. And
this is going to be just live branch.
So
um
if someone has a research question or
topic that they want to write in the
live chat then I I will prioritize that
just to uh give a fun direction
injection of of randomness. But what's
going to happen and we can start writing
out the prompt here already is
um we are going to transform using
cursor as a planner and IDE
transform
the project folders source code
manuscript and summarization
into a specific research project.
while we use the literature search
methods to
search archive for research works that
get summarized on that topic. Then we're
going to use the summarization of some
key archive works in our context window
to update the manuscript and site those
archive papers properly. So that we're
going to go using cursor
within this context of end-toend
reproducible configurable PDFs. We're
gonna go from this
template placeholder PDF
into
a uh researchbased
documentbased
open-source software packaged unitriven
development
improvable modular system with actual
reference to citations that are of the
topic that that uh someone can suggest.
But we'll start the prompt and just wait
like one more minute if anyone come does
a prompt otherwise I'll
make some
random question. Okay,
for the following topics,
make
plan to make any and all changes to only
the
project.
Okay.
All right. Gabriel export wrote
something about containment theory.
Okay. I can kind of guess what it is,
but I don't know what it is. So, um, we
will do actionable
theory, met literature, meta analysis,
and some question. Add more details if
you want about containment theory. But
first, I'm going to start the literature
review for containment theory. So,
run.sh. Step seven, literature search
PDF download.
We're going to do 50 papers, search
keywords.
Okay. Containment
theory,
comma, and Gabriel wrote alternative to
set theory. Set theory.
All right.
All right. So, this is going to you can
imagine letting this run overnight. So,
we'll just look at uh
this. This is actually going pretty
fast.
So that is going to download
the PDFs for the search that we just
made for 157
citations and add them to our
bibliography. So that's happening. Now
we're going to transform the project
folder to be a project about
containment theory and being an
alternative and implications to set
theory.
Um
we are completely
transforming
the project folder within the
constraints and niche of template slash
infrastructure methods as documented
and tested.
We are transforming
completely and only the
project
configuration
source testing
documentation
methods
rules etc. to be about
I'm writing down what Gabriel export has
written in the chat. Containment
theory
as alternative
to set theory
also known as boundary logic or iconic
mathematics.
comprehensive
bibliographic
based.
This is where we point to the summaries
because cursor can access across these
folders
for real summaries of
ref
specific
comprehensive literature review
sections.
Technical, analytical
and gestalt overview.
Unified notations and tables,
visualizations,
methods, tests.
What are the
what are the basis
implication
specific
testable
hypotheses and explanations
comprehensively.
Okay.
plan to transform
all
this is just speculative and and uh fun
but these can be tuned as well.
Transform all
sections as and all downstream. This
could be just entered in
um to a single run method.
Okay, here uh using Opus 4.5, which
within cursor is available at sonnet 4.5
cost during the first two weeks, which I
guess we're still in. Um
I should have enough usage to use opus a
bunch of times during the remainder of
this stream.
Um what's happening now as we are on now
the live branch.
So this is now
main is what I
forked to make the branch that we're now
on. So main is the one that you just
check into. And then this is now where
we're vectoring off from. We're adding
in
URLs.
Uh we're adding in doing literature
search
to uh get new PDFs and summaries. What
formulation of containment theory?
Um both since it you how should we
handle references?
We could connect to existing active
inference literature. Let's do it.
Mathematical formalism full spectrum.
So the plan mode
in cursor which
uh some or most but not all of the
models have but opus 4.5 does.
um
engages in a preliminary round of
context
iteration and refinement tool use
internally.
And we'll then write a plan
which is then sequentially with some um
uh very interestingly
controlled kind of uh stubbornness
is. So here here's what the plan looks
like. We're going to transform project
into rigorous research monograph on
containment theory. An alternative to
set theory based on G. Spencer Brown's
laws of form. Let's just see if this top
level point is like already
way off the map. We'll let it finish
writing it. Um,
oh,
containment theory replaces set
membership with spatial containment.
Okay, let's just let's let it cook
while we search.
Little pre-dinner reading.
Okay,
Gabriel in the chat and this distinction
network. So that that was also that was
uh with without
containment theory summaries in
the sum without containment theory
papers. So here we finished the 157
new papers were downloaded.
Now those are going to get iteratively
processed by Olama with a llama uh lama
gradient
local llm call
ye 1997 variational.
Let's just look at the PDF.
Ye variational.
So this is this is going to start making
a summary of this 1997 paper.
So you can imagine that with a more uh
powerful
compute which might be done one or a few
times at a few different lengths or
formats
with uh old PDFs but that's done once
per paper. So that is going to be
plugging away.
It's not going to come into
uh
use probably in this stream
because
uh a few only a few will come into play.
We'll we'll see. Maybe we'll just let it
run and we'll get like 10 summaries.
Then we could ask, okay, would these 10
new specific papers add to the paper to
make it specifically in relation to this
citation, that citation, that one? Okay,
so while we're thinking about this kind
of meta meta review literature
summarization paradigm,
the containment theory plan is underway.
So here within
project
So here's the agent
implementing that plan.
So it started by this is all heavily
signposted in the documentation and the
cursor rules and and everything.
So the config file of within the project
was changed to containment theory
boundary logic as alternative foundation
to set theory name. I'm going to just do
stream
and I'll put real email.
All right.
Uh some tests
config.yaml
the full
uh so here's configurable title
here. Here it'll just be example author
information,
publication, keywords, metadata, and
which languages we want to translate the
uh abstract to in that language step.
Then in the SRC folder,
it next implemented a 525 524 line code
boundary logic forms.
This module implements the fundamental
structures of G. Spencer Brown's laws of
form 1969 providing a computational
foundation for boundary logic as an
alternative to traditional set theoretic
foundation. The primary distinction or
mark creates inside outside
relationships replacing set membership
with spatial containment
possibly like a sort of discretization
topology as in duality with a continuous
information geometry.
Key concepts
form a recursive structure of nested
boundaries.
very relevant
Mark the primary distinction creating
inside outside
geometry
um the bubbles trilogy by slaughter dyke
of course synergetics tetrahedral as
minimal space enclosing system isotropic
vector matrix
void empty space the absence of
distinction
cross the mark state true so that's kind
of intraactivity,
a fundamental relationality,
unity and duality,
uh interactionism.
And
to what extent this is true, someone
more specifically can tie to the
literature. Um or we could have primed
with the PDFs of these textbooks and
papers specifically. So, let's
look up. Let's start another literature
search.
Run
literature search PDF download
30 papers. G Spencer Brown.
So then uh this is going to continue.
But then you can imagine that in let's
say
um 10 to 15 minutes
we will be able to say okay update
the
containment
methods in light of the formalisms
exactly like in these papers and make
sure you cite
Okay. So, we'll just we'll quit that
process
and just focus on the
um
focus on just the search for G. Spencer
Brown. So that's the only literature
search
thread.
Now
we have
still
the SRC methods getting written by the
opus 4.5 agents in the project of
pivoting project folder to be about this
research question.
So meanwhile just to get some
information.
So in Yep.
So this one
this is
containment
lit
this one
manuscript
end to end
dot slash run
the full pipeline.
So
this is going to first erase the output
directories in the project level and at
the repo level. Set up the environment
and check all the needed package
dependencies at the infrastructure and
at the project level.
First run the infrastructure test suite.
This is just to get early warning before
getting at all into the package.
Making sure that all these like 1600
tests at the repo level are very strong.
Now we're going into the test suite. Now
the test suite failed because it didn't
hit 70% coverage. That's another sort of
early warning flag just to exit.
Um so that there's end to end viability.
Um it I'm sure there are as in in this
moment excursions from that end to end
but it's kind of like sobbing breathing.
uh seems good to keep it on the rails
and then if you want to change some
aspect or remove some aspect that can be
easily done. But there's something nice
about that run
halting at uh uh ordering which is
configurable
um for that one option. But you can run
other options like if you don't want to
render the manuscript, if you just want
to do literature search, then the um the
fact that the manuscript won't render
render doesn't halt the literature
search download summarization.
Still, we have the agent plugging away
on
the code.
we can look at the plan and basically
see if the next strategy
okay so after so first the source module
so that's where what's happening
diagrams py is happening
looks like that was not included in the
original plan but I guess hey plans
We'll see after this
um
diagrams finishes maybe that will finish
this first section on the source modules
and then there will be these rewrites of
the manuscript
uh sections.
Okay,
that was there was the the thought
there. Quote thought good progress.
Now I need to update the init.py then
create the test suite. Let me continue.
So completing the test suite
confirming the functionality of the SRC
that just happened
will
raise our test coverage to 70%
in a few minutes. So we will get past
this threshold.
So this that will be a good pace.
Meanwhile, let's check back in
containment.
All right. So, we're Let's look at a
containment theory summary.
Okay.
Let's see.
There could have been citations in
different fields that that do or don't
have primary relevance to what we're
studying here.
or what are we studying here? But
let's see. All right, we have [snorts]
expected performance of the Atlas
experiment.
The Atlas detector. Wow,
how relevant. How cool.
[sighs]
Many author paper
title instability
coupling P modes and G modes within
neutron stars on GW170817.
Okay.
B particle mu decay
[sighs]
high energy nutrinos.
Not sure
if these are the papers that we are
looking for but again it's a uh
example of what can be curated in this
repo
by by anyone who would like to explore.
Meanwhile let us remember that we have
54%
with 320.
Let's run it again. So we have
54% 320
going to run the whole pipeline.
So as we made no changes to
infrastructure
54 320
we will expect homeostatically
that the infrastructure 1600 tests
fully pass
and and some of the slower ones could be
skipped. some of the LLM methods are are
skipped
because they're they're long generation
or maybe somebody doesn't even want to
use the local LLM methods at all which
are not required for the manuscript
being generated but those passed. So now
we move into the okay then right off the
bat
we get we hit now the test errors within
within the package.
So, just to kind of keep things on the
rails,
going to reync
here are the
current
test
results of the
project.
Replan it.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay.
So now the plan is being updated.
It's about pi test. So some files are
going to be
updated at these specific planned
locations.
Then we will get to the manuscript
getting written. Oh, J1 J2. That's so
funny.
Here, let's do a little J1 J2
lore.
Those are two of the
lineages that need each other
as it were of the pogamir
southwest US species concept that I did
my
PhD dissertation in in this region.
So it's just funny because it was a J1
and J2 population. So let's see what J1
and J2 do here.
um
opus 4.5
improving the intra package test suite
then once that happens we will get
through that next step of running the
manuscript end to end
because we kind of don't even want to
look at the manuscript if we don't even
have the tests functional. Um, and once
we do this initial pivot, which is still
in in progress, then we'll be kind of
switched over all the way to this other
vector. But now we have these small
edits which go relatively fast
in
phase one. Updating the source files.
Now updating the imports.
Definitely a fun way to see a lot of
sample size and learn a lot about coding
and Python.
Seeing it all even when it's not it's
not uh 100% but it is
vast
and accurate in many ways. not always in
the only way or in the specific way uh
unspecified but some of these coding
practices
are are really interesting to see just
flexible at this level and with um
opus and a lot of other models right
now.
Okay.
All right, [sighs]
back to the agenda while we give it a
little time. Just, you know, give it
like 20, 30 minutes.
We've only given it a few. All right, so
we uh
ran run.sh SH talked about these two
kind of branches of project level test
orchestration analysis rendering and
then on the literature search branch
the um tools to do research
summarization which then we can drag in
and you can say okay now take this file
into account
when writing this manuscript which is
going to be one of our next steps.
um project from scratch. The topic was
brought up to do this containment theory
topic and we're able to touch upon in in
this direct uh show and or tell strategy
with live stream interactivity.
A lot of these different aspects of meta
science or just science itself
like structure and function and
different ways to think about the
science ecosystem as different kinds of
or organizing processes processes with
different information flows taking a
systems view also firsterson view as a
navigator epistemic forger in that space
and uh just modernity and and it all
motivating this is the ability to
increase the quality and quantity and
the reproducibility and integrity of
scientific work and bridge and upskill
and and upniche and leave it better than
we started with respect to open science
and all that there's this two-layer
architecture
where infrastructure literature docs
test, scripts, and run.sh all apply to
this infrastructural kind of oven glove
handler level. And then project is
intended to be this standalone.
We'll just say um now just get to
focusing on the manuscript updating
can do code later
keeping in mind using the very most
relevant
specific citations of.
So here's the project kind of reaching
outside of its own folder
and then using
cursor
like rag
to softly access the information
geometry of summaries or or there could
be another rag call or an o lama call to
this folder. Um
then use the bibliographic information
and bibliographic
format
of the enforced by and and acted upon by
the infrastructure methods
within
the output within the project folder
manuscript.
So then we'll have our library PDF
uh
downloaded papers other documents
summarized however we
uh want to LLM summarize them
done done by a community for thousands
of papers or done by one person for even
even thousands of papers as it's going
through dozens just on this laptop. top
here
um
within a end to end versionability
setting.
So now we're going to run the full
pipeline. We expect to have the
infrastructure tests pass
and then the package tests fail.
Comprehensively
fix all
project scale methods and tests
documentation
as will pass
70% coverage.
We expect the infrastructure 1600 to
proceed.
We expect to surface some of the errors
uh from the SRC project SRC in the
coming few seconds. There we go. Two
errors.
Make sure that everything is synced. Now
with these two
agents
vectors
which can kind of co-coordinate
through the sync vector embedding of
cursor
in kind of coming up for error I I think
either at the prompt user inter
interface level or in between these
smaller steps.
Um, now we have the tests
which we want to get to 70% so then we
can get to the manuscript rendering and
the analysis and service the next level
of of errors.
Now we're already writing the paper.
[snorts]
So building on G. Spencer Brown's laws
of form 1969. We develop a complete
computational framework for boundary
logic that demonstrates its equivalence
to boolean algebra while offering
distinct advantage in parsimony,
geometric intuition, and handling of
self- reference.
This work establishes containment theory
as a viable alternative foundation for
discrete mathematics with complete
computational verification of its
theoretical claims and open- source
implementation for further
investigation.
So that sounds like something that uh
would require that kind of theorem
proving environment. Uh we do we will
find out whether that check written by
the abstract is going to be
upheld by the analysis.
but we're chugging away. Or we could
tone back whether it's a formal proof
and just feed in say we want these seven
papers to be included in a more of a
literature metaanalysis paper
or or maybe we'll see what this
literature review
um document looks like. Meanwhile, we
have the
fixing of
test errors.
Let's just more generally run the
literature summarization step just
because we're not using the LLM
otherwise
um generate summaries for download PDFs.
So first that's going to try to
redownload
missing PDFs.
We have 922 papers. 167 need download.
583 need summaries.
So we'll just let that run.
We have the
now it's iteratively running and
reingesting
the project level test suite
which is going to um give it a few
rounds of being able to feed in the
errors in the failing test. So we can
also peep that button and look in
sometimes you can't see it because of
the piping command
but um we can see it kind of ticking
away here. So that's within this cursor
infinity window
here it's testing the algebra
complexity. Then over on this one, we
still have the
references.
Here are the Wow. Calfman CS Pierce.
This is awesome.
Say excellent. Ensure that one of the
supplemental sections is a
comprehensive, vast,
formal, concise
representation
and grounding in with the history of
North American
pragmatism and
neo materialism.
just to sort of mix it up.
So, we'll see. Will it finish so then
accept this cued message or will it
finish a series more methods and then
Okay,
we'll just send that one down just so we
kind of get through to it.
Okay, test suite is ongoing.
run
sh again run full pipeline
or we could just do
run sh to run project tests.
Okay,
so I'm going to stop this one.
just to give it a re context
comprehensively fix all the project
tests.
Okay, hope I can finish this in the next
few minutes. Let's just review the
um
okay we'll look at that for sure.
So we have project tests
developing
plan in progress.
Here is the philosophical
esso. So
introduction
G. Spencer Brown
distinction
structure.
Supplement one is like a technical code.
Supplement two is
axiom verification.
So this this can be pure equation play
with with vast painting. That's the kind
of recipes that you may or may not be
able to to come through on
and or can be injected or confirmed
equivalent to formal theorem proving
andor numerical simulation steps in the
SRC of the project.
Then we have this new
so this is the okay CS Paris
developed existential graphs a
diagrammatic logic that anticipates
Spencer Brown's calculus in fundamental
ways the connection is not merely
superficial but structural
very cool
very knowledge graph pled
very computational
semantics. William James, John Dwey
to exist is to be in a situation which
is in the technical direction the kind
of minimum system start with universe
two eyes open approach of synergetics.
It's
Dean's sort of zoom in zoom out. It on
the performative side is more like
situationism or all these other kind of
math art or uh art related aesthetics.
Alfred North
Whitehead
the category of the ultimate Karen Bar.
I know from the paper of Mao and Ali
that that Barad's agential realism is
related
virtual and the actual deloo
onto power core commitments. So this is
very long
the tour. So even to the limited Donna
Heroay
even knowing this in a limited capacity
that seems to be Richard Rory
lot of crossover there.
Right. So we have
documentation getting updated at the
level of the project to reorient it
towards being stably for this
containment theory approach.
Here
we have
still
the thinking happening
with the test.
We'll just say
get going.
But that part could range from this is
sort of now the lower bar is that kind
of thinking that was just being quote
shown or quote thinking that was being
shown
and that could include MCP
or other orchestrated calls to doing
more specific theorem proving in
methods.
So
ensure all
project
methods and tests are.
This is going to be a little bit of uh
these sometimes can can uh
interfere with each other's work with
fixing different tests, but we'll just
run these two
because they'll probably be staggered in
how they run tests.
Um so as long as we keep refreshing the
context,
we should be good there. and just let us
check how many run project tests.
So that's what it's running that in this
agentic
tab. [sighs]
All right. So, so 16 failed and and we
will not move forward until those.
We could also just ask,
is there a way to
accept
failing tests and still proceed?
So targeting test failure by test
failure.
We're in the most proximal semantic
context
to
the bibliography and the claims in the
manuscript for the SRC. So that's the
sort of standalone dual channel
semantics
is the formal and the pros methods as
well as a secondary documentation layer
to to connect any needed dots like like
just sort of lab materials to make an
integrated unity
and coherent functionality at the
project level the briefcase level and
then we're in the document factory
with the infrastructural layer
And so partially just to maintain that
end to end functionality whatever
pattern that name is
a high threshold
is kept for the tests
just so that there's minimal drift away
into like a nonfunctional regime which
might come through a uh a alley into a
new zone of of improved functionality,
but then that should be branched and
then brought back in modularly.
So on this stream uh we we may only in
the next few minutes uh get to that PDF
rendering,
but suffice to say that I I can let it
run while I continue doing the rest of
uh work and play and arts and crafts
today
and just upload the the PDF which would
go to the outputs PDF folder.
and uh Gabriel export. I hope that that
this
gives some
some idea of what the system can do for
everyone. So I appreciate the
suggestion. We have abstract
the introduction
that we looked at the methods
theorems
experimental
computational kind of irreducible
complexity. Ruleadian
acknowledgements
appendix.
Yeah, I would love to see the output
too. I want to stay a few minutes just
to get there. appendix symbol glossery
and that that can be checked between the
names of the variables in the SRC and
then within and across manuscript
sections
references is a placeholder for the bib.
Yeah. Wow. Thought for 4 minutes and
40th. Okay. So, wow.
Okay,
let's run it again and see how many
failing tests. 16
488.
Run project tests.
This is the most recent test run.
Fix everything given the current state.
Yeah.
Just reync it.
Let the other one also continue to run,
but let this one do a little plan.
Actually, stop that one just so that
we're down to just a few failed six.
So, finish these six tests.
That might take a minute to skip
through. So meanwhile
comprehensively review
all the manuscript sections. It is
making
maximal compliant
real use of all relevant
citations from
literature.
Just let it run.
We'll just say mark
them and remove the block for now. We
will fix later
just so that we get to the manuscript.
Okay. So now we have
let's
Wow. Looking at the six remaining
failures, they all relate to a single
issue. The excluded middle.
How deep?
Okay. Adding the decorators so that we
can proceed hopefully through those
tests.
Now comprehensively proceed to one by
one fix
and confirm all those tests.
So now that's going to fix the six.
So that might fix these six once these.
Okay, now
we will do run.sh. We'll just we'll just
run the full pipeline and just hope that
this is going to work. Meanwhile, open
up the cursor. Okay, it's not going to
show us until it finishes.
So here we have
close that
here was from that background process of
getting the PDFs. Looks like we didn't
get any PDFs,
but it's about to Oh, maybe.
But then it's about to uh
enter into the summarization phase of
these 167.
Right. Meanwhile, all right, here we go.
So now we got further in.
So now we're generating the slides. So
now we're in project
output PDF.
Okay.
So now it's
here are the slides.
Now here's introduction. So this is the
autogenerated slides
notation.
Here's the
experimental results
TOC tax.
Here's
methodology slides,
then PDF
paper.
Boom.
So red red letter
scarlet letter text play rubrication
document structure
there's a reference error but these get
flagged
so you you can fix and then also the
iterative feedback is okay well equation
crossing is not proper
there's some visualizations some tables
there's the citations
so
very cool end of stream I am going to
end it there I hope people
enjoy and find it. Well, till next time.